<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Lewis Westbury</title>
        <link>https://instantiator.github.io/</link>
        <description>Lewis Westbury</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 17:30:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate>
            <atom:link href="https://instantiator.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
    <title>Querying data files with terminal tools</title>
    <link>https://instantiator.github.io/posts/q/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 17:30:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://instantiator.github.io/posts/q/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[There are a many ways to peek inside a data file and reason about its contents. This post is about a triplet of simple, easily available tools that I&rsquo;ve found handy for searching and querying common data file formats. You might too&hellip;
   format tool notes     CSV q Query CSV files with SQL-like SELECT statements.   JSON jq Look inside JSON files.   YAML yq Look inside YAML files.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Choosing your first coding language</title>
    <link>https://instantiator.github.io/posts/what-language/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 15:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://instantiator.github.io/posts/what-language/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Anyone can code. This is a short exploration of the choices for coding beginners out there.
There&rsquo;s nothing unique about coders (other than choosing to code) and certainly no reason to believe that your gender, age, or any other characteristic is going to hold you back. Anyone who tells you differently is gatekeeping, and that&rsquo;s not kind. If you want to get started, read on&hellip;
Chef Gusteau would like to remind you that coding is for everyone, and why wouldn&#39;t it be?]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Keeping jobs alive with caffeine</title>
    <link>https://instantiator.github.io/posts/caffeine/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 19:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://instantiator.github.io/posts/caffeine/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[My Mac likes to go to sleep to save power, and that means any long-running processes I have underway will be suspended when it does.
Until recently, I had assumed my best option was to change the power settings. For tasks I want to keep alive, there&rsquo;s a better option - called caffeine, available on OS X and Linux.
Just like time (a tool to tell you how long a task took to run), you can prefix a command with caffeine.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Hello, World!</title>
    <link>https://instantiator.github.io/posts/hello-world/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 22:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://instantiator.github.io/posts/hello-world/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I learned to code on a computer called the BBC Micro, released by the BBC in 1981. I was also released in 1981, and I have a bit of a bond with these 8-bit wonders. Coding is a joyous experience, and anyone can learn to do it. This is a post about retro-coding, and my first written post for this blog.
pic.twitter.com/y5zy1P2TAE
&mdash; BBC Micro 🎄 Bot (@bbcmicrobot) March 1, 2020  Hello, World!]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
